A Finding Aid to the Robert Smithson and Nancy Holt Papers, 1905-1987, bulk 1952-1987, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Interview Transcripts, 1966-1973; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 11 Folders Box 2
  This series includes nine interview transcripts with Robert Smithson. Topics include his general philosophy on art; contemporary art in relation to its historical context; non-sites, earthworks, entropy, space, and structures; the relationship between artists and dealers, museums, and collectors; and his most influential works, including Spiral Jetty, Broken Circle, and Spiral Hill.
  The Alan Kaprow and Rodger Katan transcript (1966) focuses on the relationship between museums and contemporary art. The transcript with Dennis Wheeler (1969-1970) consists of 4 taped, informal sessions discussing Smithson's general philosophy on art, non-sites, and specific projects. In the Paul Toner transcript (1970), Smithson discusses earthworks, mirror displacements, non-sites, and art's historical context. The Gregorie Muller transcript [1971] focuses on the background and construction of Broken Circle and Spiral Hill. The Art Institute of Chicago transcript (1971) records Smithson's question and answer session with the audience after a showing of his films Swamp and Spiral Jetty. In the Bruce Kurtz transcript (1972), Smithson informally discusses artists' relationships with dealers, museums, and collectors; gallery art's general separation from nature; capitalism's influence and intersection with art; and his 1966 airport projects.
  The Stella Russell (1973) transcript focuses on Spiral Jetty, Broken Circle, and Spiral Hill. In the Alison Sky transcript (1973), Smithson discusses his thoughts on entropy, the act of building, and its intersection with the architectural and engineering mechanics of structure. In Smithson's transcript with two unidentified students (1973), he discusses modernism and the branching off of developing contemporary art; public sculpture; historical context, theory, linguistics, and humanism; and thoughts on his own writings. The transcript with Moira Roth (1973) focuses on Duchamp and conceptual art.
  There is also a full transcript of the Andrew Dickson White Museum's Earth Art Symposium (1969) with the following participating artists: Mike Hiezer, Dennis Oppenheim, Robert Smithson, Neil Jenney, Gunther Uecker, Jan Dibbets, Richard Long, and Hans Haacke.
  This series is arranged in chronological order by year of the interview.
  - Robert Smithson and Rodger Katan with Alan Kaprow, "What is a Museum? Notes of Meeting on Museums", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Transcript of Earth Art Symposium, Cornell University, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Robert Smithson with Dennis Wheeler, 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Robert Smithson with Paul Toner, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Robert Smithson with Gregoire Miller, circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Robert Smithson at the Art Institute of Chicago, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Robert Smithson with Bruce Kurtz, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Robert Smithson with Stella Russell, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Robert Smithson with Alison Sky, "Entropy Made Visible,", 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Robert Smithson with Two Students, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Robert Smithson with Moira Roth, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Writings, 1959-1975; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Writings consist of drafts of published and unpublished essays by Smithson on art, artists, and works in progress. The series also includes poems by Smithson, six notebooks containing notes and sketches by Smithson, and drafts of writings sent to Smithson and Holt by friends and colleagues, including Carl Andre, Terry Atkinson, Dan Flavin, and Dan Graham.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  4.1: By Robert Smithson, circa 1959-1973
  4.2: By Others, 1962-1975
  - By Robert Smithson, circa 1959-1973; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    Writings by Smithson consists of 73 handwritten and typescript outlines, essay drafts, and lectures Smithson wrote from the 1960s to 1973. The majority of these writings explore his thoughts on contemporary art and artists. Through the theoretical frameworks that incorporate history, linguistics, aesthetics, literature, and media studies, Smithson examines historical and contemporary art's evolving concepts of interpretation and meaning, and specifically, the effect capitalism, nature and the environment, minimalism, and conceptual absences were having on his own art.
    Essays of note include "The Crystal Land" (1966), "Cultural Confinement" (ca. 1972), "Frederick Law Olmstead and the Dialectical Landscape," (ca. 1973), "Incidents of Mirror Travel in the Yucatan" (ca. 1969), and "See the Monuments of Passaic New Jersey" (1970).
    The subseries also includes six notebooks that record project ideas, fragments of essays, and letter drafts; a series of 21 poems written by Smithson on Christian/religious themes; and miscellaneous handwritten and typescript notes on art and film. Notebooks I and VI include notes by Nancy Holt.
    - "Abstract Mannerism", circa 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - "Art and Dialectics", circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Art and the Political Whirlpool or the Politics of Disgust", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "Art and Time", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - "Art and Truth", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - "Art Through the Camera's Eye", circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "Artist as Site-Seer", circa 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - "Better Homes and Industries", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - "Broken Circle, Emmen, Holland", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - "Can Man Survive?", circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - "Cinematic Atopia", circa 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - "Collossal Nullifications", circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - "Critoid Menace", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - "Crystal Land", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - "Cultural Confinement", circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - "Dialectic of Site and Non-Site", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Domain of the Great Bear", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Earth Art and Reclamation", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "Earth Projects (A Sedimentation of the Mind)", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Ecology and the Incest Taboo", 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Economics of Self in Nature and Art", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Establishment", 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Esthetics of Disappointment", circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Fiction and Language in Art", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "First Louse on the Tip of a Penis", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Frederick Law Olmstead and the Dialectical Landscape", circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "From Ivan the Terrible to Roger Corman or Paradoxes of Conduct in Mannerism as Reflected in the Cinema", circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Hidden Trails in Art", 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Hotel Palenque", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "Iconography of Desolation", 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Illustrations of Catastrophe and Remote Times", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Incidents of Mirror-Travel in the Yucatan", circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Interstellar Flit", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "Lamentations of the Paroxysmal Artist", circa 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letter to Michael Fried, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Look", circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Minus Twelve", circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "Modular Properties in Structural Art", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "Museum of Language in the Vicinity of Art", 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Nature and Abstraction", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "New Monuments and Entropy", 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "Note on the Division of Esthetics", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "Notes for the Tape Recorder", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - On Donald Judd, Drafts and Fragments, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - On Donald Judd, Complete Draft, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - On Donald Judd, Copy B, circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Outline for Yale Symposium: Against Absolute Categories", 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Paragraph from a Fugitive Artist's Journal", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "Pathetic Fallacy in Esthetics", circa 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "Picturable Situations and Infra-Maps", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "Pointless Vanishing Points", 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "Primary Envelopment", 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "Production for Production's Sake", circa 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Quasi-Infinities and the Waning of Space", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "Recent Site Developments", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "Refutation of Historical Humanism", circa 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "Restorations of Prehistory", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "Search for the Elusive Edge", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "Secrets of the Ambulatories", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "Secrets of the Dome", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - "See the Monuments of Passaic, New Jersey" Draft, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - "See the Monuments of Passaic, New Jersey", 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - "Shape of the Future and Memory", circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "Sites and Settings", circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - "Small Test for Jo Baer", 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - "Some Void Thoughts on Museums", circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - "Sonsbeek Unlimited - Art as an Ongoing Development", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - "Space, The Mirror of Time", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "Strata, A Geophotographic Fiction", 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - "Toward the Development of an Air Terminal Site", circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - "Towards a Pornographic Art Criticism", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - "Two Attitudes Toward the City", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - "What is an Art Show? A Paper Tiger", circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - "What Really Spoils Michelangelo's Sculpture", circa 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - "X Factor in the New Art", circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Notebook I, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Notebook II, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Notebook III, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Notebook IV, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Notebook V, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Notebook VI, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Poems, circa 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Typescript, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Handwritten, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, On Films, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - By Others, 1962-1975; 4.2; Archival Resource Key
    Writings by others includes unpublished draft versions of essays and fictional works sent to Smithson and Holt by friends, colleagues, and students of art criticism. Smithson is the topic of two personal reminiscences by Carl Andre and Jack Thibeau and seven academic essays examining his work and influence.
    The scholarly essays include Janet Kardon's "Robert Smithson's Unrealized Projects," William Lipke's "Dialectics of Place: Some Reflections on Robert Smithson's Mirror Project," and Joseph Masheck's "Smithson's Earth: Notes and Retrievals." Though there is no attributed author of the essay "Non-Sites," the draft has been edited by Robert Smithson.
    Other writings include two project proposals by Dan Graham, a project proposal by Terry Atkinson, writings and a speech by Dan Flavin, and a draft of "Idea Art" (1968) by Howard Junker.
    - Andre, Carl, [On Robert Smithson], 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Atkinson, Terry, "Three Boxes", circa 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Baker, Kenneth, "Note on Criticism as Fiction", circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Fischer, Candace, "Labyrinth", circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Flavin, Dan, [Excerpt from a Letter and a Record Entry], 1966; 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Flavin, Dan, "Speech for the Senior and Graduate School Students at the Rhode Island School of Design", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Graham, Dan, "Dislocations", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Graham, Dan, "TV Camera/Monitor Performance", 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Junker, Howard, "Idea Art", 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Kaprow, Allan, "Where Art Thou, Sweet Muse? (I'm Hung Up at the Whitney)", 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Kardon, Janet, "Robert Smithson's Unrealized Projects", circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Kubler, George, [On Prime Objects and Replications], From The Shape of Time, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Lipke, William C., "Dialectics of Place: Some Reflections on Robert Smithson's Mirror Project" (Cayuga Salt Mine Project), circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Masheck, Joseph, [Annotated Chronology of Smithson Projects, 1964-1973], circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Masheck, Joseph, "Smithson's Earth: Notes and Retrievals", 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Mussman, Toby, "Alchemist", 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Mussman, Toby, "Pierrot-Le-Fou - Godard as Godard", 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - O'Doherty, Brian, "Less Known and Unknown: An Exhibition of 35 Painters", circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Oster, Gerald, "What's Op?", 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Robbin, Anthony, "Some Common Misconceptions About Smithson's Conceptual Art", circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Robbin, Anthony, "Zen", circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Rubenfeld, Florence, [On Robert Smithson], 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Shafrazi, Tony, "Thats It", 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Stitelman, Paul, "Light and Video: Contemporary Art and Technology", circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Swenson, Gene, "Way of Art: A Comedy in Six Scenes", circa 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Thibeau, Jack, "Los Cines", 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Thibeau, Jack, [On Robert Smithson], circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Unknown, "Non-Sites", circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 98)
- Project Files, circa 1950s-1982; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 6.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-5, Boxes 17-18, OV 20, OV 22-26, OV 36, RD 28-30, RD 32-35
  Project files contain correspondence, project instructions, diagrams and sketches, research materials, photographic material, and maps related to over 50 of Smithson's artworks. These include concepts, proposed projects, sculptures, non-sites, and earthwork projects, including Spiral Jetty, Broken Circle, and Spiral Hill.
  The series also includes miscellaneous textual and graphic research material collected by Smithson but unrelated to any specific art project.
  The series has been arranged alphabetically by project name.
  The bulk of this series has been digitized. Items not digitized include some commercial maps and brochures with no annotations, for which only the covers have been digitized; duplicate photographic material; and some oversized maps and documents that cannot be digitized due to size.
  - 400 Seattle Horizons, Seattle, [Washington], 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Aerial Art", circa 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Alogon, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Amarillo Ramp, Amarillo, Texas, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Amarillo Ramp, Amarillo, Texas, Oversized, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Asphalt Rundown, L'attico, Rome, Italy, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, Emmen, Holland, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, Emmen, Holland, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, Emmen, Holland, Maps and Brochures, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, Emmen, Holland, Photographic Material, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, Emmen, Holland, Oversized, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 22, Folder 1)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, Emmen, Holland, Oversized, 1971-1982; Archival Resource Key (Roll 28)
  - Broken Map, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Roll 29.
  - Broken Map, circa 1960s-1973; Archival Resource Key (Roll 29)
  - Central Park (Frederick Law Olmstead), New York City, New York, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Central Park (Frederick Law Olmstead), New York City, New York, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Central Park (Frederick Law Olmstead), New York City, New York, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Circular Ramp (Promontory), circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Oversized material digitized with Box 17, Folder 2
  - Circular Ramp (Promontory), Oversized, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Coastal Crescents, Salton Sea Project, California, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Coastal Crescents, Salton Sea Project, California, Oversized, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Concrete Pour, Chicago, Illinois, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Earth Map for Mexico (Gondwanaland), 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Earth Map for Mexico (Gondwanaland), Oversized, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 22, Folder 2)
  - "Eliminator", 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - First Upside-Down Tree, Alfred, New York, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Florida Projects, 1969-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Florida Projects, Oversized, 1969-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Florida Projects, Hypothetical Continent of Lemuria, Sanibel Island, Florida, 1969-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Florida Projects, Mirror Shore, Sanibel Island, Florida, 1969-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Flows and Pours, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Flows and Pours, Oversized, digitized with Box 4, F23, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Flows and Pours, Oversized, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Roll 32)
  - Force-Findings of the Termites, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Gyrostasis, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "Hum", circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Hypothetical Continent in Stone: Cathaysia, Alfred, New York, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Interpolation of the Enantiomorphic Chambers", circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Island of Broken Glass, Vancouver, Canada, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Island of Broken Glass, Vancouver, Canada, Oversized, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Island of Broken Glass, Vancouver, Canada, Oversized, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Roll 29)
  - Lake Crescents, Forest Park, Illinois, 1970-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Lake Crescents, Forest Park, Illinois, Oversized, 1970-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Lake Edge Crescents, Ohio, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Mirror Displacement, Cayuga Salt Mine Project, Ithica, New York, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Mirror Displacement, Cayuga Salt Mine Project, Ithica, New York, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Mirror Displacement, Cayuga Salt Mine Project, Ithica, New York, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Mirror Displacement, Cayuga Salt Mine Project, Ithica, New York, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Mirror Displacement, Cayuga Salt Mine Project, Ithaca, New York, Oversized, digitized with Box 4, Folder 32, Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Mirror Displacements, England, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Mirror Displacements (England), Oversized, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 22, Folder 3)
  - Mirror Project, Amsterdam, Holland, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Mirror Project, Rome, Italy, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Mirror Project, Rome, Italy, Oversized digitized with Box 4, Folder 38, 1968-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "Monument" (Film Project), circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Monuments of Passaic, Passaic, New Jersey, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Monuments of Passaic, Passaic, New Jersey, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Monuments of Passaic, Passaic, New Jersey, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Monuments of Passaic, Passaic, New Jersey, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)